A Guide to the Louis Arthur Johnson Papers, ca. 1930-1964
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
- Series V. Papers of the Secretary of Defense
  - Subseries A, General Correspondence
    - Correspondence re: National Industrial Conference Board Dinner 1950 Sept. 8-16 (Box 138)
    - Correspondence and Papers, Miscellaneous invitations for speaking engagements 1949 Nov.-1950 Sept. (Box 138)
  - Subseries B, Safe-File, 1949-1950
    - File of Correspondence and Memoranda from the Secretary of Defense's Safe-File mainly official and political material, Index included, A-M, 5 folders 1949-1950 (Box 139)
    - File of Correspondence and Memoranda from the Secretary of Defense's Safe-File mainly official and political material, Index included, N-W, 3 folders 1949-1950 (Box 140)
  - Subseries C, Engagements Calendars
    - Engagements Calendar, Secretary of Defense Louis Johnson, 4 folders 1949 March 28-1950 Sept. 19 (Box 141)
    - Two lists entitled, "Future official or Out-of-Town Engagements" 1949 Oct. 7-1950 Sept. 24 (Box 141)
  - Subseries D, Speeches, Press Releases, Conferences
    - Oath of Office 1949 March 28 (Box 142)
    - Press Conference 1949 March 29 (Box 142)
    - U. S. S. Roanoke Commissioning, Philadelphia 1949 April 4 (Box 142)
    - American Society for Newspaper Editors 1949 April 22-29 (Box 142)
    - Statement in support of North Atlantic Treaty 1949 April 28-1950 March (Box 142)
    - Chamber of Commerce 37th Annual meeting 1949 May 5 (Box 142)
    - Cornerstone Laying New American Legion Building, Indianapolis 1949 May 6 (Box 142)
    - National Board of Fire Underwriters N. Y. C. 1949 May 26 (Box 142)
    - Memorial Day Remarks 1949 May 30 (Box 142)
    - Honorary Degree citation, Creighton University 1940 June 2 (Box 142)
    - Creighton University Commencement, Omaha, Nebraska 1949 June 2 (Box 142)
    - NME Savings Bond Rally 1949 June 3 (Box 142)
    - Villanova College Commencement 1949 June 4 (Box 142)
    - Yeshiva University, N. Y. C. 1949 June 12 (Box 142)
    - National War College 1949 June 21 (Box 142)
    - Statement on Procurement of Contracts by Business 1949 June 21 (Box 142)
    - Red Cross Annual Convention - Atlantic City, N. J. 1949 June 29 (Box 142)
    - W. Va. State American Legion Convention, Wheeling, W. Va. 1949 July 4 (Box 142)
    - Statement in support of Military Assistance Program 1949 July 29 (Box 142)
    - Statement before Investigation Subcommittee 1949 Aug. 8 (Box 142)
    - CBS Series on the Nation's Defense, D. C. 1949 Aug. 22 (Box 142)
    - Statement on B-36 Investigation, House Committee on Armed Services 1949 Aug. 23 (Box 142)
    - Marx Leva Statement on B-36 Program 1949 Aug. 23 (Box 142)
    - Conference and Statements on Reduction of Costs 1949 Aug. 24 (Box 142)
    - American Legion Distinguished Service Medal to the President 1949 Aug. 29 (Box 143)
    - American Legion Convention, Philadelphia, Pa. 1949 Aug. 31 (Box 143)
    - Theatre Owners of America, California 1949 Sept. 15 (Box 143)
    - Statement on Alaska at Press Conference, L. A. 1949 Sept. 15 (Box 143)
    - American Ordnance Association, New York City 1949 Sept. 21 (Box 143)
    - American Federation of Labor Annual Convention, St. Paul, Minnesota 1949 Oct. 10 (Box 143)
    - Statement before the Committee on Armed Services, House of Representatives 1949 Oct. 10, 21 (Box 143)
    - Freedom House Award to General Clay 1949 Oct. 13 (Box 143)
    - Civilian Personnel Policy 1949 Oct. 14 (Box 143)
    - Statement of Herbert Hoover before the Armed Services Committee of the House of Representatives 1949 Oct. 21, 24 (Box 143)
    - New York Herald Tribune Forum 1949 Oct. 26-Nov. 25 (Box 143)
    - Address of welcome by the Honorable Louis Johnson, to the Military Procurement Seminar 1949 Nov. 1 (Box 143)
    - American Automobile Association, Cleveland 1949 Nov. 2 (Box 143)
    - Off-the-Record Remarks of Louis Johnson, Meeting of Executive Committee, American Legion, Indianapolis 1949 Nov. 5 (Box 143)
    - American Legion Meeting, Indianapolis 1949 Nov. 5 (Box 143)
    - Armistice Day Address 1949 Nov. 11 (Box 143)
    - Speech, New England Conference of Governors, Boston 1949 Nov. 17 (Box 143)
    - New England Council Annual Meeting 1949 Nov. 18 (Box 143)
    - "The Ramparts We Watch," before the Congress of American Industry 1949 Dec. 7 (Box 143)
    - New York County Lawyers' Association Dinner 1949 Dec. 21 (Box 143)
    - Statement of Louis Johnson before the House Committee on Armed Services re: B-36 investigation ca. 1949 (Box 143)
    - Press Conference Budget 1950 Jan. 10 (Box 143)
    - "Armed Forces Hour" Television Series, Washington, D. C. 1950 Jan. 15 (Box 144)
    - House Armed Services Committee 1950 Jan. 20 (Box 144)
    - Chamber of Commerce, Roanoke 1950 Jan. 25 (Box 144)
    - Statement before Senate Foreign Relations Committee 1950 Jan. 26 (Box 144)
    - Joint Chiefs of Staff Press Conference 1950 Feb. 13 (Box 144)
    - U. S. Attorneys Conference 1950 Feb. 14 (Box 144)
    - Press Release re: the Service Academy Board 1950 Feb. 16 (Box 144)
    - Senate Committee on Expenditures in the Executive Departments 1950 Feb. 28 (Box 144)
    - Overseas Press Club of America, Waldorf-Astoria 1950 Feb. 28 (Box 144)
    - Statement before Senate Appropriations Committee, 1951 estimates 1950 March 3 (Box 144)
    - Address before Irish Fellowship Club of Chicago 1950 March 17 (Box 144)
    - Flight of 4 B-29s under MDAP, Andrews Air Force Base 1950 March 20 (Box 144)
    - Founder's Day remarks, U. of Va., Charlottesville 1950 April 13 (Box 144)
    - Statement of Secretary of Defense Louis Johnson before Armed Services Subcommittee of the Senate Appropriations Committee, 1951 Budget 1950 April 26 (Box 144)
    - Statement before the Armed Services Committee of the House of Representatives in Executive Session 1950 May 3 (Box 144)
    - Speech before Kiwanis Club, Miami, Florida 1950 May 11 (Box 144)
    - Armed Forces Day, Statler Hotel, Washington, D. C. 1950 May 19 (Box 144)
    - Armed Forces Day Banquet, Waldorf Astoria, N. Y. C. 1950 May 20 (Box 144)
    - Outline for Memorial Day 5 minutes speech 1950 May (Box 144)
    - Statement before Armed Services Committee, United States Senate 1950 June 1 (Box 144)
    - U. S. Naval Academy Graduation 1950 June 2 (Box 144)
    - Commencement, Pennsylvania Military College 1950 June 6 (Box 144)
    - Industrial College, Washington, D. C. 1950 June 27 (Box 144)
    - Reserve Officers Association 1950 June 2 (Box 144)
    - Senate Foreign Relations and Armed Services Committees 1950 June 5 (Box 144)
    - Remarks before the Reserve Officers Association, Mayflower Hotel, Washington, D. C. 1950 June 28 (Box 144)
    - Statement before Senate Appropriations Committee 1950 July 25-26 (Box 145)
    - Statement of Louis Johnson before the Senate Appropriations Committee 1950 July 26 (Box 145)
    - Statement before Senate Appropriations Committee 1950 July 26 (Box 145)
    - Radio Broadcast, Three Star Extra 1950 July 27 (Box 145)
    - Statement of Louis Johnson before the Armed Services Subcommittee of the Committee on Appropriations, House of Representatives 1950 Aug. 2 (Box 145)
    - Statement before the Armed Services Subcommittee of the House Committee on Appropriations 1950 Aug. 2 (Box 145)
    - Statement before the Foreign Relations Committee, U. S. Senate 1950 Aug. 17 (Box 145)
    - Statement before Committee on Armed Services, U. S. Senate 1950 Aug. 22 (Box 145)
    - West Virginia American Legion Convention 1950 Aug. 26 (Box 145)
    - Statement before the Committee on Appropriations, U. S. Senate 1950 Aug. 30 (Box 145)
    - Letter from Secretary of Defense Johnson to Representative Anthony F. Tauriello 1950 Aug. 31 (Box 145)
    - Joint Meeting American Bar Association and Canadian Bar Association 1950 Sept. 18 (Box 145)
    - Remarks of Louis Johnson at the 32nd Annual National Convention of the American Legion 1950 Oct. 9 (Box 145)
    - Remarks, Past National Commander of the American Legion at its 32nd Annual National Convention 1950 Oct. 9 (Box 145)
    - Statement before Senate Foreign Relations Committee re: Military Preparedness n. d. (Box 145)
    - Statement by Secretary of Defense Louis Johnson re: Membership on Board of Consolidated Vultee Aircraft Corp. n. d. (Box 145)
    - Miscellaneous notes for speeches, found in Johnson's desk ca. 1949-1951, n. d. (Box 145)
    - Transcripts of Louis Johnson's Press Conference 1949 March 29-1950 Feb. 13 (Box 145)
    - Transcripts of Statements by Louis Johnson before Congressional Committees, 1949, with an Index, 2 folders 1949 April 21-Oct. 21 & 1950 Jan. 20 - Aug. 30 (Box 146)
    - Press Releases, 2 folders 1949 March 26-1950 Aug. 4 (Box 146)
    - Press Release, 2 folders 1950 Aug. 16 (Box 146)
    - Press Release re: Louis Johnson's request for Congressional approval of a Universal Training Act. 1950 Sept. 13 (Box 146)
    - Department of Defense, Digest of News (Box 146)
  - Subseries E, Miscellaneous
    - Typescripts of Staff Meetings of the Secretary of Defense and his staff 1950 Jan. 13-July 3 (Box 147)
    - Address List - Democratic National Committee 1949 (Box 147)
    - Address List - Foreign Diplomatic, Defense Ministers 1949 (Box 147)
    - Address List - Joint Civilian Orientation Conference 1949 (Box 147)
    - "Christmas Cards Sent" Listing 1949 Nov. (Box 147)
    - North Atlantic Treaty Organization Directory 1950 June 23 (Box 147)
    - Directory and address list, Office of the Secretary of Defense 1949 Nov. 14 (Box 147)
    - Address List - Press, Public Relations 1949 (Box 147)
    - Telephone Listings - Army, Navy, Air Force, and Boards, including several lists of luncheon guests and lists of invitations regretted 1949 Oct.-1950 July (Box 147)
    - Address List - U. S. Diplomatic Service 1949 (Box 147)
    - DS (copy), Appointment of Louis Johnson as Secretary of Defense 1949 March 23 (Box 147)
    - TMs (carbon), Summary of the accomplishments of the Department of Defense 1950 Sept. 16 (Box 147)
    - Biographical information re: Louis Johnson ca. 1931-ca. 1955 (Box 148)
    - "Civilian Radar Training Program, for United States of America," [by Charles Mills] 1950 July (Box 148)
    - Concluding remarks of the Honorable Herbert Hoover at the dinner given for visiting publishers at the Walforf Astoria Hotel, by Neal Dow Becker 1949 April 26 (Box 148)
    - "Daily Summary," National Military Establishment, Office of Public Information, mainly re: Forrestal's resignation 1949 March 4-11 (Box 148)
    - Draft of a bill to provide family allowances for dependents of enlisted members of the Armed Forces 1950 July 25 (Box 148)
    - Copy of Harry Truman's report to Congress on the Korean situation 1950 July 19 (Box 148)
    - Legislative Program for 1950, Dept. of Defense 1949 Nov. 22 (Box 148)
    - List of persons invited to "Swearing-In" ceremonies 1949 March 28 (Box 148)
    - Miscellaneous items ca. 1949-ca. 1950 (Box 148)
    - Miscellaneous Newsletters 1950 (Box 148)
    - National Security Act Amendments of 1949 - compiled by L. H. Renfran, Marx Leva 1949 (Box 148)
    - "News of the World, WRC-NBC," Louis Johnson, the Tornado that walks like a man 1949 Aug. 24 (Box 148)
    - North Atlantic Treaty, Hearings before the Committee on Foreign Relations, U. S. Senate 1949 April 27-29, May 2-3 (Box 148)
    - Notebook of Quotations, with an Index [ca. 1949-ca. 1950] (Box 149)
    - Preliminary Draft, Office of National Mobilization, Mr. Louis A. Johnson - No. 11 n. d. (Box 149)
    - Miscellaneous Programs 1949-1950 (Box 149)
    - Draft (photocopy), Public Law 253, 80th Congress, Chapter 343, An Act to promote the national security by providing for a Secretary of Defense 1949 March 2 (Box 149)
    - "Report for the Department of the Air Force on the Material Organization of the United States Air Fore" 1950 Aug. 15 (Box 149)
    - Revitalizing a Nation, a statement of Beliefs, Opinions and Policies embodied in the Public Pronouncements of General Douglas MacArthur 1952 (Box 149)
    - "The Ryukyus," a brochure re: Okinawa for Louis A. Johnson 1950 June 22 (Box 149)
    - Draft of a letter on Universal training for possible use by the President n. d. (Box 149)
    - West Virginia Department of Veterans Affairs Annual Report 1950 July (Box 149)
    - 2 TMs (copies), "A Study of Witch-hunting and Hysteria in the United States" 1950 Aug. (Box 149)
- Series VI, Miscellaneous Papers of Louis Arthur Johnson
  - Subseries A, Correspondence
    - American Bar Association to Louis Johnson 1956 Jan. (Box 150)
    - Correspondence with Wm. Wallace Barron 1963 Nov.-Dec. (Box 150)
    - TLS, Madame Chiang Kai-shek to Louis Johnson 1958 Nov. (Box 150)
    - TNS from Wm. R. Daley to Louis Johnson 1951 Feb. 13 (Box 150)
    - TN, George Davis to Louis Johnson 1955 June 8 (Box 150)
    - Correspondence with Dwight D. Eisenhower 1961, 1963 (Box 150)
    - Correspondence with various people re: James Forrestal ca. 1955-1961 (Box 150)
    - Correspondence with Roswell Gilpatric 1961 Aug. (Box 150)
    - TNS, Frances Holsclaw to Mrs. Nutter w/enclosure 1965 Sept. 9 (Box 150)
    - Correspondence with the Herbert Hoover family 1964 Oct. (Box 150)
    - Correspondence with President Lyndon Johnson 1963-1964 (Box 150)
    - Correspondence and Papers with White House, President John Kennedy 1961-1964 (Box 150)
    - Correspondence with Robert F. Kennedy 1960-1963 (Box 150)
    - L. L. Lemnitzer, Chairman, Joint Chiefs of Staff to Louis Johnson 1962 Aug. 9 (Box 150)
    - Correspondence in re: to the McArthur hearings 1951 June-July (Box 150)
    - Correspondence and Papers re: the MacArthur Hearings, Testimony of Louis Johnson 1946 (1950-1951) (Box 151)
    - TLS, Douglas MacArthur to Louis Johnson 1961 July 14 (Box 151)
    - Correspondence re: Manufacturers Record1955 July (Box 151)
    - R. B. Nutter to Louis Johnson 1952 March 10, 11 (Box 151)
    - Correspondence and Papers with John Osborne re: Forrestal biography 1948-1949 (1962-1963) (Box 151)
    - Correspondence with James E. Powers, National Commander, The American Legion 1963 Aug. (Box 151)
    - TNS, A. C. Spurr to Louis Johnson 1956 April 18 (Box 151)
    - Correspondence with Harold Stagg, speech writer 1950-1952 (Box 151)
    - Correspondence with Lewis L. Strauss, Chairman, Atomic Energy Commission 1954, 1959 March-June (Box 151)
    - Correspondence with Admiral Clifford A. Swanson 1962 January (Box 151)
    - Postcard from Bradley Taylor 1955 June 28 (Box 151)
    - TNS, Harry Truman to Louis Johnson 1965 Dec. 17 (Box 151)
  - Subseries B, Speeches and Miscellaneous
    - Remarks of Louis Johnson, Charleston Chamber of Commerce Annual Membership Dinner, West Virginia 1950 Nov. 16 (Box 151)
    - TMs (copy) Address of Senator Richard B. Russell at Jefferson-Jackson Day Dinner 1953 Feb. 28 (Box 151)
    - TMs (photocopy), The Untold Story of Douglas MacArthur, by Frazier Hunt, p. 466 1954 (Box 151)
    - Certificate, West Virginia Service Officers School, Veterans' Service Training 1955 May 22 (Box 151)
    - Article, "What Are the Communists' Objectives?" by Louis Johnson 1955 Sept. (Box 152)
    - Speech of Louis Johnson at Dedication of Memorial Hall, Potomac State College, West Virginia University 1957 Jan. 13 (Box 152)
    - Certificate, Fifty Years Service in West Virginia Bar Association 1963 Aug. 30 (Box 152)
    - TMs(carbon), Speech, "Concepts for Total War: Nature of the Conflict - Requirements for Survival and Victory" n. d. (Box 152)
    - TMs(carbon), speech re: Korean War, rough and unedited n. d. (Box 152)
    - TMs(carbon), Speech re: spreading isolationism n. d. (Box 152)
    - Declaration of decision, not to run for the Senate nomination n. d. (Box 152)
  - Subseries C, Printed
    - Report of Proceedings, Hearing held before Committee on Armed Services and Committee on Foreign Relations, (vol. 35), 2 volumes 1951 June 14 (Box 152)
    - Report of Proceedings, Hearing held before Committee on Armed Services and Committee on Foreign Relations, (vol. 36) 1951 June 15 (Box 152)
- Series VII, Photographs
  - Photograph of Johnson's swearing-in as Assistant Secretary of War 1937 March (Box 153)
  - Photograph, Newly appointed military attache calling on Assistant Secretary of War 1937 Sept. (Box 153)
  - Photographs, Grafton Municipal Hospital under construction by the WPA, W. Va. ca. 1937-ca. 1940 (Box 153)
  - Photograph of Johnson's Trip to Seattle, Washington, W. P. A. Officials Dinner ca. 1937-1938 (Box 153)
  - Photograph of Johnson speaking against the Ludlow Bill 1938 Jan. 6 (Box 153)
  - Photograph, Assistant Secretary of War, Louis A. Johnson standing by his own official airplane 1938 Jan. 10 (Box 153)
  - Photograph of Louis Johnson with W. Ross McCain 1938 Jan. 20 (Box 153)
  - Photographs of Johnson addressing American Airlines, Chicago, Ill. 1938 Feb. 2 (Box 153)
  - Photographs of Johnson at Amon Carter Dinner, Texas 1938 Feb. (Box 153)
  - Photographs of the XB-15, an army experimental plane 1938 April (Box 153)
  - Photographs of Ft. Leavenworth 1938 June 30 (Box 153)
  - Photograph Album, Visit of Louis Johnson to Fort Lewis, Washington 1938 July 14 (Box 153)
  - Photograph, Louis Johnson in Alaska 1938 Aug. 22 (Box 153)
  - Louis Johnson, Assistant Secretary of War and J. Monroe Johnson, Assistant Secretary of Commerce with crew of Army Y1-OA-8 1938 Aug. (Box 153)
  - Photographs of Louis Johnson and J. Monroe Johnson during a trip to Ketchikan, Alaska; Views of Alaska 1938 Aug. (Box 153)
  - Photographs, Johnson's visit to Gulfport, Miss 1938 Sept. (Box 153)
  - Photographs of Johnson at the Wine Association meeting and at Detroit Ordnance 1938 Oct. 19 (Box 153)
  - Photograph of Assistant Secretary Johnson and Assistant Secretary Edison leaving the White House after a conference with Roosevelt 1938 Oct. 25 (Box 153)
  - Photograph, Assistant Secretary of War Johnson and Assistant Secretary of Navy Charles Edison 1938 Oct. 28 and n. d. (Box 153)
  - Photographs of Assistant Secretary Johnson with F. D. Roosevelt, President 1938 Oct.-1940 April (Box 153)
  - Photograph, open-cockpit plane, Ryan Co. 1938 Dec. (Box 153)
  - Photograph of a portrait of General John J. Pershing 1938 (Box 153)
  - Photographs of Louis Johnson 1938-1940 (Box 153)
  - Photographs of Johnson at various Jackson Day celebrations 1939 Jan. (Box 153)
  - Photograph, Henry Morgenthau, Jr.; Rep. Andrew J. May; John W. Hanes; Harry Woodring; and Louis Johnson, after the Senate Military Affairs hearing 1939 Feb. 16 (Box 153)
  - Photographs of W. Va. Air Cadets, Class 39A at graduation, Randolph Field, Texas 1939 Feb. (Box 153)
  - Photograph, Mrs. Caroline Eldridge Hamner visiting Secretary Woodring, Assistant Secretary Johnson, and Chief of Staff, General Malin Craig 1939 April 13 (Box 153)
  - Photographs of Assistant Secretary Johnson at the Industrial Preparedness Luncheon 1939 June 20 (Box 153)
  - Photographs of the John S. Brookes Party, Louis-Galento Fight, New York 1939 June 28 (Box 153)
  - Photograph, Interdepartmental Conference, State, War and Navy 1939 Aug. 24 (Box 153)
  - Photographs of the Dallas, Oregon Speech by Johnson 1939 Aug. (Box 153)
  - Photographs of Louis Johnson at Uniontown, Pa. 1939 Aug. (Box 153)
  - Photograph, Johnson and the Aerial League of America at the N. Y. Worlds Fair 1939 Oct. 27 (Box 153)
  - Photograph of Tony, a horse at Fort Bragg 1939 Oct. (Box 153)
  - Photographs of Johnson addressing the B'Nai B'Rith, New York 1940 Feb. 25 (Box 153)
  - Photograph of Secretary of Interior, Harold Ickes 1940 Feb. (Box 153)
  - Photographs of the Association of American Railroads Dedication of a tablet to soldiers of railroad background, with Dan Willard and Louis Johnson 1940 April 26 (Box 153)
  - Photographs of Plane Makers meeting officials re: defense 1940 May 20 (Box 153)
  - Photograph of Johnson and A. P. E. Doyle, National Committeeman, at the Democratic National Convention 1940 July 18 (Box 153)
  - Photograph of Louis Johnson, Wendell L. Willkie, and Irvin S. [Cobb] 1941 July 26 (Box 153)
  - Photograph of Louis Johnson, giving an address [ca. 1941?] (Box 153)
  - Photograph of Louis Johnson and [N.] G. [Carell] 1943 Jan. 28 (Box 153)
  - Photograph, Gov. Prentice Cooper, Gov. Dwight Griswold, Louis Johnson, Cordell Hull, Warren Atherton, and Gov. Leverett Saltonstall 1944 Feb. (Box 153)
  - Photograph, Rear Admiral Sidney W. Souers, USNR, of St. Louis, director of new Central Intelligence Agency 1946 Jan. 23 (Box 154)
  - Photograph, Col. Robert J. Wood 1947 June 12 (Box 154)
  - Photographs, Captain Robert W. Berry, USN 1947 Sept. 22, n. d. (Box 154)
  - Photograph, Gordon Gray, Assistant Secretary of the Army 1947 Sept. 23 (Box 154)
  - Photographs, Inauguration of President Harry Truman 1949 Jan. (Box 154)
  - Photographs, Mr. Johnson succeeds Mr. Forrestal as Secretary of Defense 1949 March 28 (Box 154)
  - Photograph, Secretary of Defense at his first Press conference 1949 March 29 (Box 154)
  - Photographs, Meeting of Secretary of Defense with Secretaries of the Army, Navy, and Air Force 1949 March 29 (Box 154)
  - Photograph of Louis Johnson and others, by M. R. Ashworth, Publisher, Columbia, Ga. 1949 April 11 (Box 154)
  - Photograph, Johnson testifies on the Atlantic Pact 1949 April 28 (Box 154)
  - Photograph, Swearing-in of Mr. Stephen A. Early as Under Secretary of Defense 1949 May 2 (Box 154)
  - Photograph of Johnson's Medal of Merit 1949 May 5 (Box 154)
  - Photograph, Secretary Johnson at an American Legion Parade, Fort Ben Harrison 1949 May 11 (Box 154)
  - Photograph, Secretary of Defense buys first Poppy 1949 May 19 (Box 154)
  - Photograph, Model Airplane entrants meet Secretary of Defense Johnson 1949 May 27 (Box 154)
  - Photographs, Secretary Johnson shows his application for a U. S. Savings Bond, aerial view of the Bond drive 1949 June 3 (Box 154)
  - Photographs, Secretary Johnson at Villanova dedication exercises 1949 June 4 (Box 154)
  - Photograph, Louis Johnson receives an honorary Doctor of Laws degree, Marietta College 1949 June 5 (Box 154)
  - Photograph, Lewis Johnson at laying of corner stone for Legion building, Indianapolis 1949 June 6 (Box 154)
  - Photograph, Swearing-in of Doctors Allen and Meiling, N. M. E. Medical Services Division 1949 July 6 (Box 154)
  - Photograph, Secretary Johnson confers with General Omar N. Bradley 1949 July 28 (Box 154)
  - Photograph, Secretary Johnson greets various visitors 1949 July-Sept. (Box 154)
  - Photographs, Boys' Forum of National Government visits the Pentagon 1949 Aug. 1 (Box 154)
  - Photograph, Philippine President visits Secretary of Defense 1949 Aug. 10 (Box 154)
  - Photograph, President Truman signs the Unification Bill 1949 Aug. 10 (Box 154)
  - Photographs of Louis Johnson's visit to Ottawa, Royal Canadian Naval Photographs 1949 Aug. 11 (Box 154)
  - Photographs, Swearing-in of General Omar N. Bradley as 1st Chairman, Joint Chiefs of Staff 1949 Aug. 12, 16 (Box 154)
  - Photograph, Armed Forces Policy Council Meeting 1946 Aug. 16 (Box 154)
  - Photograph, Secretary Johnson testifies at B-36 investigation 1949 Aug. 23 (Box 154)
  - Photographs, Secretary Johnson greets members of the American Legion Auxiliary's Girls' Nation 1949 Aug. 25 (Box 154)
  - Photographs of President Truman and Secretary Johnson in a motorcade American Legion Convention 1949 Aug. 29, 30 (Box 154)
  - Photograph, Official Reviewing Party, American Legion Convention, Philadelphia 1949 Aug. 30 (Box 154)
  - Photographs, President Truman receiving the American Legion Distinguished Service Medal, American Legion Convention, Philadelphia; General Bradley 1949 Aug. 30 (Box 154)
  - Photograph, Wall display of photographs, American Embassy, Guatemala 1949 Aug. (Box 154)
  - Photograph, Mr. Thomas R. Reid, receives award, departing Chairman of the Personnel Policy Board 1949 Sept. 1 (Box 154)